All right. So as in the last video, I told you that there's a better way, much
succinct way to traverse an area in Java now. And I told you that I'll keep
you updated with the with the recent changes that have been made from time to
time in the language. And one of those was the enhanced for loop. And it was
specifically introduced for a couple of reasons. The first one being arrays and
the second one being collections. And we are in good spot right now to use that
with an area. And that is the Java five enhanced for looping. Other languages
they call in the for each, but Java thought that the designers thought that
it's still the Java for loop. Right. It's not for each. So why should we just
stick to calling in the for loop, but enhanced and more intelligent as you're
going to shortly find out. And as you look at line number 20, this perfectly
works fine, but, but it looks a bit laborious. You have to put in the
internalization, the condition, the increment agreement and get the values
out of it, which shortly would look more like like mid-age. Right. And that is
we have, I'll just put in the comments for you. I'll just say the Java five
enhanced for loop. And the syntax for doing that is you just say a four and then
you say variable declaration. And then you say name or array or collection. By
the way for now, let's just stick to array. Once we come across collections,
then we can use the same enhanced for loop for collections as well. So and this
is where it's where it gets different. That is you just need to declare a new
variable here. And the rule is the type of that variable should be the same as
of the type of this area. Right. That's very important. Otherwise, it won't
work. Okay. Now, you declare a variable, then instead of a semicolon, you
just say a column and then the name of the array, which you're going to
traverse, which you're going to deal with, which you're going to get the
values out of. Right. So put that here. And no internalization required. No
condition, no increment agreement, because it's an intelligent form of the
for loop. That is, that's why it's called the enhanced for loop. So following
the syntax, let's go on and do this with the enhanced for loop. I'll just
comment this, I'll say, or with Java, five enhanced for loop. Okay. How do we do
that? I'll say a four and the variable type this time is long, which we're
going to traverse. Right. I'll say long value, name of value, array is values
appropriately. See, the benefit you derive from naming your identifiers
appropriately, this is values, which is more than one values. That's why
it's an array. This is a value, which is one value. And then go on and do
whatever you want to do with this value. That's it. Shorter precise,
succent less verbos coding. You hit run. Let's see if this still works. And as works
like a charm, but without that laborious steps, right? No need to put in the
internalization. What you need to do is how does this work? You say long
value, right? So it's a call in values. So what it does is it intelligently
gets the first value out of first index at zero index, puts it into this
variable, and then you are free to do whatever you want to do with that variable.
Remember, if you did it with the what we now call after Java five, we started
to call this as a traditional for loop, because it had a tradition. It was
there from the times of C and other languages. But now this is new. Since this
come in, came in, we call this the traditional for loop, right? So now with
the enhanced for loop gets the value, right? You print it out. You don't need to
write it now. What looks like the ugly way, array of index, no directly, say
value, right? And then you go on the loops, loop moves on to the second iteration.
Intelligently moves the cursor one step forward, gets you the value from the
second index that in our case is one and puts it into this particular variable.
And then you're free to do whatever you want to do. No increment,
tickling and require no condition. And then once it reaches the end of the array,
intelligently gets you out of the for loop, right? So that is why it's called
the enhanced for loop, because it produces succinct code less verb or scored.
No angelization, no conditional increment agreement, but does the same job, but
for all its glory, the enhanced for loop remains less flexible, less strong
than the traditional for loop. That's why the traditional for loop is still
used in the language, right? Why do I say so? Because the enhanced for
loop can only work in forward on the direction. If you have to get back
from the array in reverse order, you have to go back and use the traditional
for loop, right? And the enhanced for loop can only work with areas or
collections. But the traditional for loop can be used to print for
but not see series can be used to get you prime numbers, print different
series and even work with areas and collections. That's why it's more
flexible, more stronger. This is not so, but for this kind of a situation
where I just have to travel to an array in forward only direction, I
definitely use the enhanced for loop. And I hope you would agree with me as well.